all right what's going on everybody it's
you bro hope you're doing well and in
this video i'm going to help you get
started with html so sit back relax and
enjoy the show
if you wouldn't mind please like comment
and subscribe one like equals one prayer
for the youtube algorithm
i'm gonna tell you why you should learn
html html is an acronym for hypertext
markup language it's the most basic
building block of the web it allows you
to add change and remove website content
and that's a good thing to know it's
mandatory to know for web developers if
you would like to enter that career
field it's useful for software
developers marketing and sales
professionals if you need to edit a
listing for your company business owners
you could make your own website and
freelancers people would pay good money
for a good website heck you might as
well add html to your resume can't hurt
and learning html is super easy this
full course is only going to be about an
hour anybody can learn html even you yes
whoever's watching this video learn html
it's super easy what do you have to lose
building a website is a lot like
building a house first we need a solid
foundation and we need to build a
skeletal structure that's where html
comes in it's the most basic building
block of the web then after that we can
add css css is cascading style sheets
with css we can style color and change
the appearance of a webpage and lastly
there's javascript javascript adds
functionality to a webpage so in a house
this could be like plumbing heating and
air conditioning and electricity so it
adds functionality and when you combine
these three levels you have a good
functioning webpage but you need to
start somewhere so that's why you're
gonna learn html first what will you
need you'll need a web browser use
whatever web browser that you like just
please do not use internet explorer and
we'll also need a text editor to write
html code you can use vs code sublime
text heck you can even use notepad but i
prefer vs code so i'll show you where to
download that head to
code.visualstudio.com and download the
correct version for your operating
system i'm running windows so i'm going
to install the windows version then i
will open when done
accept the agreement
yes i actually did read it that fast i
would recommend creating a desktop icon
and make sure add to path is selected
next and install and then you might as
well launch this bad boy so finish we
are now within vs code the first thing i
recommend is to download the live server
extension so that after saving an html
document we can immediately refresh a
web page so underneath the search box
for extensions we are looking for live
server and install this version then
after downloading the live server
extension we will create a new folder
under the explorer tab open folder
wherever you want create a new folder
i'll create this on my desktop just for
convenience i'm going to create a new
folder i'll name this website
or whatever you want doesn't matter
then select folder and within our
website folder we're going to create a
new file name this index.html
whatever file you would like to be the
home page of your website you'll want to
name that as
index.html when a connection is made to
a website without a specific file in the
url most servers by default will return
the
index.html file as a landing page so
this index.html file will be the home
page the landing page of our website at
the top of our document we're going to
type this within angle brackets
exclamation point doc type html
html documents should start with this
declaration to be compliant with basic
html standards it lets a visitor's web
browser know that this is an html5
document and following this text will
create a pair of html tags tags are the
keywords within angle brackets that a
web page uses to define how your web
browser will format and display content
and usually these come in pairs so we'll
need an opening html tag and a closing
html tag all of our html code will be
within these html tags so the html
element represents the root of an html
document and there's two major sections
head and body so let's create a pair of
head tags head represents information
about a web page and there is also body
as well so create a pair of body tags
the body is what you would like to
display to a user the head is
information about the web page one thing
that we can add to the head of our
document is a title so we'll need a pair
of title tags
and let's create a title for our website
my
first website and then let's save let's
open this document so i'm going to right
click open with live server so the title
of this web page is my first website and
you may have noticed that this web
browser was opened with edge so you can
actually change that to a different web
browser and here's how go to file
preferences
settings
underneath extensions head to
live server config
custom browser and select a web browser
of your choosing so right click open
with live server and we are now using a
different web browser so i'm just going
to put my web browser and vs code side
by side
now let's add some text to the body of
our webpage type whatever you want i
like pizza
then i'm going to save
there we go we added some text to the
body of our html document and we can
also use a pair of header tags so
surround some text with h1 this is the
largest header tag and then make sure to
close it afterwards okay so then we have
h2 which is smaller
we have h3
h4
h5
and the last one is h6
so if you need some sort of title for
your web page you can always play some
text within a pair of h1 header tags
before i discuss p tags we should
discuss what elements are elements
embody the opening tag any content
within and the closing tag so for
example this is a opening title tag and
a closing title tag and all of these
together including any content within is
known as the title element so that's the
difference between tags and elements
tags make up a portion of elements and
with that out of the way we can move on
to paragraph elements paragraph elements
are made up of p tags we need an opening
p tag and a closing piece egg and we can
type some text within these paragraph
tags
this is some sample text browsers
automatically add a blank line of before
and after any paragraph elements also if
you need some longer sample text there
is a shortcut type lorem then tab
and that will create some sample text
for you and let's create another
paragraph element so we need an opening
p tag and a closing p tag i would like
some more sample text i will type lorem
then tab and we now have two paragraph
elements if you need a paragraph of
information to display with blank lines
before and after you can always surround
some text within a pair of p tags now
there's also a br element and these do
not need closing tags it's only an
opening tag wherever you would like to
add a line break just add a br element
so let's say i would like to space out
these header tags well i can add a line
break between each of these
if you ever need a line break just use a
vr element and like i said there's no
closing tag with these elements there's
also an hr element and i do not mean
human resources i mean horizontal rule
if you ever need to divide your page
section by section you can always add a
horizontal rule let's say that we have a
title to this webpage i'll create an h1
header tag this is my website
and then i'm just going to close this
what if i would like to divide this
webpage section by section i can always
add a horizontal rule by using an hr
element and there is no closing tag with
this element you just type hr with an
angle brackets and this will divide a
section of your webpage and add a
horizontal rule which looks pretty nice
so that is the hr element and the last
thing we're going to discuss for this
topic is comments comments will not be
displayed within the body of your
document it's more or less a note for
yourself or other developers to create a
comment we need an angle bracket
exclamation point then two dashes and
this will create the ending of your
comment which is an arrow pointing to
the right so anything between these two
arrows will be a comment i'll leave a
comment for i don't know myself
this is the best website ever
so as you can see this will not be
displayed within my webpage it's
basically used as a note for yourself or
for other people looking over this html
document so yeah those are comments well
everybody that is the basics of html so
yeah if you liked this video please give
this video a thumbs up leave a random
comment down below and subscribe if
you'd like to become a fellow bro
hey what's going on everybody it's you
bro hope you're doing well and in this
video i'm going to show you how we can
have some fun with hyperlinks and html
so sit back relax and enjoy the show
if you find this video helpful please
remember to like comment and subscribe
your support will help keep this channel
running
sup people so hyperlinks we can apply a
hyperlink to text buttons images
elements of that nature whatever you
would like to turn into a hyperlink
surround with a pair of a tags
there's an opening a tag and a closing a
tag and within the opening a tag there
is an href attribute that you can set to
a url of your choosing so if i want this
hyperlink to take me to google then i
will fill out the url for google
so after saving if i click on this link
it takes me to google easy enough right
now there is a target attribute you can
open a web page in a new tab or window
by setting this to underscore blank
so this should open in a new tab or
window
but the default is self
so that this will open in the same
window there is a title a title is a
small pop-up box that will appear when
you hover your cursor over this link we
could write a message like this
takes you to google
and that box should appear after you
hover your cursor over this hyperlink
this takes you to google let's say you
have another webpage and you would like
this link to take you to your second
page let's change the text
uh go to page two i'm going to create
another html file real quick i'll go to
new file let's call this page two dot
html
if you need to generate the necessary
body of an html document if you're using
vs code you can type exclamation point
and then tab
and let's write a message
this is page two
if i set the href attribute equal to the
relative file path of whatever page i
would like to go to then this hyperlink
will take me there so these files are
right next to each other i only have to
list the file name so i would like this
hyperlink to take me to page2.htm
so if i click on this hyperlink
it will take me to my other html file
this is useful if you have a navigation
bar so depending on the link that
somebody clicks on your navigation bar
that can take you to a different page
and lastly you can send an email to
somebody within the href attribute type
mail to colon then some email address
let's say fake123 gmail.com
let's say email me instead
and then when you click on this link it
will begin the process of sending an
email
but we won't actually complete it so
yeah everybody those are hyperlinks you
can apply hyperlinks to text buttons
images which we'll have some practice
with in the future so yeah those are
hyperlinks and html
all right people here's how to add an
image to a web page find or download an
image of your choosing i just so happen
to have a picture of shrek within your
folder containing your index.html file
you're going to move or paste that image
within the same folder and within the
body element we're going to create a new
element an image element within angle
brackets type img for image this is a
self-closing tag and many elements have
different attributes that we can change
we need to change the source attribute
of this image element the source
attribute is src and we will set this
equal to within double quotes the name
of our image mine is shrek.png and then
save
what i like to do if i'm working with
the webpage that has a lot of images i
like to create a separate folder for my
images this isn't necessary but if your
image is located within a separate
folder we need to find the file path
relative to your index.html file so i'm
going to create a new folder and let's
name this images it will contain all the
images from my webpage then i will move
my image to my images folder so we can
no longer locate this image we need to
find the file path relative to the
index.html file to look within my images
folder i will precede the image name
with
forward slash the name of the folder
images slash the name of the image and
there it is personally if i'm working
with a lot of images i like to place all
of my images within one folder if you
decide to do that as well you just need
to precede the file name with the name
of the folder that it's in here's my
image but it's fairly massive we can
change the width and height attributes
if we need to i will change the height
attribute height equals maybe 200 and
that's a lot smaller maybe 300 that's a
little bit better the height and the
width will scale proportionately with
each other but you can change them
individually let's change the width
width equals
let's say 100
what we get is an extra skinnyshrek and
if i change this to maybe 600 well shrek
is extra thick now so i will just only
change the height attribute so that the
width attribute scales proportionately
now if somebody is visually impaired
they may be using a screen reader to
navigate a web page it would be good
practice to add some alternative text
that is read out loud by a screen reader
so that is the alt attribute within
double quotes i'll type a brief
description of this image
this is a picture of shrek so when you
add an image it's considered good
practice to add some alternative text
you can also add a title too a title
will be a small pop-up box that appears
when you hover your cursor over an image
to add a title set the title attribute
equal to some text
uh shrek is
shrek see
and then i'm going to save hover my
cursor over the image and we can see a
small pop-up box that has my title shrek
is shreksy we can also turn an image
into a hyperlink to turn this image into
a hyperlink we need to surround our
image element with an opening and
closing a tag
so open and close within the opening a
tag there is an href attribute that we
can set to a url of our choosing i think
i'll set this hyperlink to the wikipedia
page for shrek so just type in the url
between these double quotes save then if
i were to click on my image this will
take me to the wikipedia page for shrek
or some other url depending on what you
type here so yeah that's how to add an
image to a web page within the body
element you need to add an image element
and then set the source equal to the
image name if you found this video
helpful please remember to smash that
like button leave a random comment down
below and subscribe if you'd like to
become a fellow bro
if you do need an mp3 file to work with
for this video i recommend heading to
the youtube audio library and then you
can search and download a song of your
choosing so after you find an mp3 file
you can use a wav file too just drag and
drop it to your folder containing your
index.html file and then we can head to
vs code now to add audio to our web page
we need an audio element
so within angle brackets audio and list
the source equal to the name of your mp3
or wav file we're going to need some
controls so this is a boolean attribute
we don't need to set the sql to anything
it's either true or false and to set it
equal to true you just type the name of
the attribute so within the audio
element type controls and up top here we
have our controls for our mp3 file with
these controls we can play some audio
file of our choosing
[Music]
we can fast forward
and we can mute here's a couple other
boolean attributes we can have our audio
autoplay by using the autoplay boolean
attribute
if you would like this to be muted
originally type muted so this is playing
but you can't hear it because it's muted
if you need this to loop just type loop
yep and it's looping you can have backup
audio files just in case your web
browser doesn't support a given format
so if you would like some backup audio
files we're going to change this around
a little bit so let's get rid of our
source and we'll create an audio closing
tag
and we will create multiple nested
source elements
type source
source equals the name of one audio file
you would like to use primarily if you
have a backup let's say we have the same
song as a wav file you can do that too
if for some reason the browser using
doesn't support these first two audio
files you can always display a message
this browser does not support
html5
audio so yeah everybody that's how to
add audio to a web page you just have to
use this audio element and set the
source equal to an audio file of your
choosing and there's a bunch of boolean
attributes that you can add to if you
would like some controls if you need to
set this to autoplay if you need it
muted and if you need it to loop so yeah
that's how to add audio to a webpage if
you found this video helpful please be
sure to smash that like button leave a
random comment down below and subscribe
if you'd like to become a fellow bro
all right welcome back everybody in this
video i'm going to show you all how we
can add a video to a web page you'll
need a video of one of these file types
when i was in tokyo some number of years
ago i saw a real-life mario kart racing
down the street so what i'm going to do
is place this mp4 file next to my
index.html file and then within vs code
we need a video element
and we will list the src attribute equal
to the name of our file that we're
working with
and in my case it's racing.mp4 now this
video is massive so let's change the
width of this using the width attribute
width equals what about
that's a lot better but we'll need some
controls to actually play this video i'm
clicking on this and nothing's happening
controls is a boolean attribute we only
have to list the attribute name to add
controls
there we go we now have some controls
[Music]
now if you want this to play maybe in
the background and you do not want
controls you can always set this to
autoplay
[Music]
so i'm going to add the controls back if
you need this muted just add the muted
boolean attribute
so it's playing but we can't hear
anything
and if you need this to loop just add
the loop boolean attribute and this
should loop
yeah there it is here's another thing
that we can try let's get rid of our
source attribute and we're going to
create a video closing tag
and we will create nested sources within
our video element
source src equals our video file so just
in case your browser doesn't support an
mp4 video file you can always create
another source
let's say that we have a web m file as a
backup just in case that this browser
doesn't support an mp4 file and if for
some reason that no other sources work
you can always add a note
this browser does not support
html5
audio so you can write it either way but
if you have multiple sources you can
always have backups just in case this
primary source doesn't work so yeah
everybody that's how to add a video to a
webpage if you found this video helpful
please be sure to smash that like button
leave a random comment down below and
subscribe if you'd like to become a
fellow bro
all right welcome back everybody so in
this video i'm going to show you all a
few useful text formatting tags that you
may be interested in we'll need some
sample text to work with this is normal
text we'll create additional lines of
text so i'm going to surround this text
with a pair of paragraph tags just so
that when we add additional text they
will be added to a new line let's copy
this line and paste it nine additional
times let's say
there we go first set of text formatting
tags that i'll show you is bold any text
that you need to bold just surround that
text with a pair of b tags we need an
opening b tag and a closing beats egg
this is normal text and you can see that
the word normal is bold uh let's change
that to bold just so that it's more
descriptive of what it does
okay so any text you need bold just
surround with a pair of b tags the next
set of tags is italic surround any text
that you need italic with a pair of eye
tags this is italic text we have big
this is big text
we have small
this is small text sub for subscript
this is subscript text superscript
the tag name is sup like you're saying
sup to somebody
this is superscript text we have
inserted inserted is just underlined
ins for inserted
this is inserted text
there is deleted deleted will create a
line through some text
this is deleted text and there's one
more it looks like i miscounted there's
also marked
so we use a pair of mark tags
any text that is marked is highlighted
so yeah those are a few text formatting
tags that i thought you should know if
you found this video helpful please be
sure to smash that like button leave a
random comment down below and subscribe
if you'd like to become a fellow bro
hey welcome back in this video i'm going
to show you all how we can create lists
in html there's three lists we're going
to talk about unordered ordered and
description lists let's begin with
unordered lists to create an unordered
list we need a pair of ul tags for an
unordered list and between these ul tags
we can create individual list items and
we use a pair of li tags for each item
we would like to add to our list so
what's an example of an unordered list
one thing that comes to mind is a
shopping list like a grocery list
because well i'm kind of hungry right
now it's breakfast time let's say that
we're going to bake a pizza and we need
a list of ingredients we need pizza
dough so add an item between this pair
of li tags and we now have one bulleted
item within our unordered list and let's
create another item so we can just copy
and paste this pair of li tags and
create a new list item
what about tomato sauce
and then maybe cheese
and toppings
point being to create an unordered list
you need a pair of ul tags and with each
list item you would like to add to your
unordered list you just place within a
pair of li tags for list item an ordered
list is very similar except we use ol
tags so we need an opening ol tag and a
closing ol tag so by default each list
item is going to be numbered so let's
say that we have a to-do list
to add a list item we need to use a pair
of li tags perhaps this is a schedule of
what we have to do in the morning we
have to eat breakfast
that could be one list item
so to add another item we need another
pair of li tags
then maybe we need to take a shower
so each of these is numbered and they're
in ascending order
and then we want to what about
leave for work okay so yeah that is an
ordered list the order of the list items
does matter and we can change the type
too within the opening oil tag there is
a type attribute we can set each list
item to a number a letter or roman
numerals if i would instead like letters
i can just set the type equal to a and
our list items are now marked with the
letter and we have description lists we
need a pair of dl tags for description
lists
and instead of using an li tag for each
list item we use a pair of dt tags for
description term and dd tags for
description definition so for a term
that is dt and then we add a definition
to this term let's say we have a list of
web dev languages for a term we need an
opening dt tag and a closing dt tag
and then we can add a definition to this
term so that would be dd description
definition between the opening and
closing dd tags we can add a definition
to this term
let's say that this adds
structure to a web page
and then to create another term and
definition pair we can just copy this
let's add css this adds style to a web
page
then javascript
this adds
functionality to a webpage with
description lists each list item is a
pair of terms and definitions the last
thing i'm going to show you you can
create a nested list within a list so
let's say i would like to add a sub list
of individual toppings to our unordered
list within the list item we just create
a new list let's say that i would like
another unordered list so i need a pair
of ul tags
and what are some toppings we can place
on our pizza so we need a list item
what about pepperoni
so we have a sub list going if you take
a look on the webpage right now oh then
maybe
what about mushrooms next i like
mushrooms
and
peppers i guess all right people those
are how to create lists there's three
types unordered ordered and description
lists just use a pair of appropriate
tags depending on the list you want to
use so yeah everybody that's how to
create different lists in html if you
found this video helpful please remember
to smash that like button leave a random
comment down below and subscribe if
you'd like to become a fellow bro
hey it's you bro hope you're doing well
and in this video i'm going to show you
all how we can create a table using html
so sit back relax and enjoy the show
everyone i'm going to show you all how
we can create a table using html let's
say that we have a store not an online
store but a brick and mortar store and
our job is to create a table of the
hours of operation for our store
which we can best represent with the
table on our website so to create a
table we'll use a pair of table tags
there's an opening table tag and a
closing table tag to add a row to our
table we can use a pair of tr tags for
table row and let's say that we'll have
two rows one for the days of the week
and the other for the hours of operation
so within this first row let's add some
headers using th tags for table header
and i'll list the days of the week so we
have sunday through saturday so to add
another header just use another pair of
th tags
sunday
monday
tuesday
you get the rest
table headers are inherently bold if we
would like to add some data to the
second row we'll add that between the tr
tags for the second row
so we would like some data which is td
we need an opening td tag and a closing
td tag for each cell let's pretend that
our store is open monday through friday
nine to five and closed on the weekends
saturday and sunday this first cell is
for the first day sunday the first
column
so we are closed this day let's copy our
table data element and copy it this will
be for the second row monday and we are
open nine to five and let's fill this in
for the days monday through friday
and then saturday we are closed
all right let's color in these cells
i'll make the first row a dark gray
color so to change the color of the
first row within the opening tr tag for
the first row there is a bg color
attribute which means background color
and i will set the sequel to gray and
our second row let's make this light
gray so within the opening tr tag for
the second row let's set the bg color
attribute equal to a different color
like light gray pick whatever color you
want it doesn't necessarily have to be
gray so within the opening table tag i
will set the bg color equal to what
about black
cool these cells are left aligned we can
center them to center the cells within a
row within the opening tr tag there is
an align attribute and let's set this
equal to center and the text is now
centered and lastly let's make all of
these cells the same size this wednesday
cell is taking up a lot of space let's
set the width equal to maybe 100 pixels
and i will just copy this
and with the opening table element i
will set this equal to the width of each
cell times the number of cells that we
have so if each cell has a width of 100
and there's seven cells i will set the
width equal to 700.
and well there we go all of these cells
are now aligned so yeah that's how to
create a table in html just use a pair
of table tags for each row add a pair of
tr tags if you need a row to function as
a header such as the days of the week
use th tags if you're filling in data
for a cell use td tags for table data so
yeah that's how to create a table in
html if you found this video helpful
please be sure to smash that like button
leave a random comment down below and
subscribe if you'd like to become a
fellow bro
hey uh what's going on everybody in this
video i'm going to show you how we can
add color to a webpage so sit back relax
and enjoy the show
all right now here's how we can add
color to a web page we'll be talking a
little bit about css but we'll cover
this more in depth in the css series i
thought this would be a good place for
us to introduce colors because we'll be
able to color things like buttons and
forms and whatnot here's how to add some
color to a webpage within the opening
tag of an element of your choosing
there is a style attribute and within
double quotes we can add css properties
for my website i would like to change
the background color to black because i
think it would look cool so within
double quotes list the css property you
would like to change background color
after the colon you can either add a
color name rgb values or hexadecimal
values let's just say the color black
there we go we can no longer see my
website let's change the font color of
these individual h1 header tags again
it's the same process as before
style equals
within double quotes list the css
property you would like to add
i would like to add color this time to
change the font color and i will pick
red there we go this time let's use rgb
values
so again style attribute equals the css
property would like to change
to instead use an rgb value type rgb
parenthesis then i would recommend
looking up a color picker
and you can pick a color of whatever you
would like uh what about blue
perhaps that shade of blue so rgb values
are in a group of three a triad
so i will copy these three numbers and
paste them within the parentheses of rgb
and the second h1 header tag is now that
specific shade of blue i tend to prefer
to use rgb values or hexadecimal values
over color names because you have more
variety now let's use hexadecimal values
style equals the css property
of color
so hexadecimal values always start with
a hashtag
what about green
so we'll have red blue and green and i
will copy this number they are in groups
of six and well yeah it's green now cool
right okay now let's change both the
font color and the background color of
this paragraph within the opening tag of
this paragraph element
we will set the style attribute equal
to any css properties within double
quotes
let's change the background color first
background
dash color
colon space
i'll set this to
dark gray which is
2 2 2
2 2 2 then to add multiple css
properties separate each with a
semicolon and this time i will change
just the color and i'll use the same
shade of green all right well there we
go so yeah everybody that's how to add
some colors to your webpage there's more
advanced things we can do when we reach
the video series on css but what you can
do for now within the opening tag of an
element of your choosing set the style
attribute equal
to whatever css properties you would
like to add within quotes so yeah that's
how to add color to webpage if you found
this video helpful please be sure to
smash that like button leave random
comments down below and subscribe if
you'd like to become a fellow bro
hey welcome back in this video i'm going
to explain the span and div tags let's
begin with span span adds markup to text
or portion of a document anything that i
surround with a pair of spam tags i can
apply markup or some effect to so in my
example document i have a header and
three paragraphs what if i would like
this specific sentence to be i don't
know red well what i could do is
surround this sentence in my document
with a pair of spam tags
so i need an opening spam tag and a
closing spam tag
and that sentence ends right here and
within the span tag i can change some of
the attributes of this sentence um so i
would like to change maybe the style
i'll set the style color equal to red
now you probably do want this closing
tag if you do not have this closing tag
your span will take up this entire
section
so basically that's what span is it adds
markup to text or a portion of a
document div is very similar except it
divides a division of a document so what
if i would like to change the background
color of these three paragraphs well
what we learned in the last video on
colors is that we could set the style
background
color equal to some shade of gray maybe
this value this does work and i could
just copy this and paste it for each of
these paragraphs
or another way of doing this is that i
can surround these three paragraphs with
a pair of div tags
so we need an opening div tag
and a closing div tag
and then i will apply this style
attribute to the opening div tag
and it will apply
this attribute to anything between these
div tags so yeah that's basically what
the span and div tags do span adds
markup to text or portion of a document
div defines a division of a document so
yeah that's span and div in html
yeah let's begin so meta tags the meta
element represents various kinds of
metadata that cannot be expressed using
the title base link style and script
elements metadata is data about data we
can add metadata to the head of our
document and this tells the web browser
what our web page is about with the meta
tags we place them within the head not
the body so we can tell the web browser
some information about our web page meta
tags are self closing we do not need a
closing tag meta tags do have a name
attribute that we can set to one of many
settings let's say we would like to add
a description to this webpage and the
web browser is going to read this
description after setting the name equal
to description i can set the content
equal to a brief description of my
webpage
uh perhaps free
html tutorial for beginners
okay so that's one example of a meta tag
so let's create another so meta again
these are self-closing tags and i can
add some keywords for search engine
optimization
so name keywords
content
and i'll explain my web page in just a
few keywords uh perhaps html separate
each of these with a comma
tutorial
beginners
that'd be good we can add a author
meta name
equals author
content equals and then type your name
so if somebody is viewing your web page
on a mobile device you can have your web
page scale to their mobile device by
adding this meta tag name equals
viewport
content
equals
and this will set the width of our web
page
equal to device dash width
then comma we can set the initial
scale
equal to 1.0 so by adding this meta tag
if you were to view this webpage on a
mobile device this web page will scale
proportionately with that mobile device
another meta tag is a char set
we can tell a web browser what sort of
character encoding that we're using
so authors are encouraged to use utf-8
for unicode
so if you want to use basic ascii
encoding you would write ascii here
although that's discouraged authors are
encouraged to use utf-8 for unicode
all right and the last thing i'm going
to show you is that we can set our web
page to automatically refresh after a
given amount of seconds
so meta
http
dash equiv is the attribute name
equals
refresh
and the content equals how many seconds
you would like to wait to have your
browser refresh
uh perhaps 30.
okay so i'm going to open this with live
server so if i set this to 30 seconds
it's not going to be that visible you're
gonna have to wait until we see this
refresh let's set this to something more
drastic like two seconds let's crank
this up yep see it's refreshing every
two seconds uh but let's set that back
to 30. two seconds was just an example
so yeah those are meta tags they
represent metadata
is data about data by adding meta tags
we can tell a web browser information
about our website such as a brief
description keywords author we can set
the viewport for mobile devices you can
set a refresh rate stuff like that and
then be sure to add meta tags to the
head element of your document so yeah
those are meta tags if you found this
video helpful please remember to smash
that like button leave a random comment
down below and subscribe if you'd like
to become a fellow bro
hey what's going on everybody it's you
bro hope you're doing well and in this
video i'm going to explain how we can
use iframes to embed web pages and other
documents within your website so sit
back relax and enjoy the show
hey welcome back iframes the iframe
element is used to embed content from
another source into an html document
they're commonly used for advertisements
and they're easily abused with many
hacking techniques so basically using an
iframe we can embed another web page
within our webpage or we could embed our
current html document with another html
document here's how we can create an
iframe this is a self-closing tag and we
set the source equal to this can be an
external website such as a url or we can
place a relative file path to a file of
our choosing so this doesn't work with
many websites and i'll demonstrate that
so let's set the source equal to
google.com and then save and reload so
google.com refused to connect that's
because a lot of major websites have
disabled the use of iframes since we're
embedding another web page within our
webpage a common hacking technique is
that you can have this embedded webpage
take up the entire frame of your html
document your website could pose as
another website and that could be
considered dangerous let's say that you
embed a banking website like bank of
america so if somebody visits your
website it's actually a facade and
somebody will type in their banking
information like their login credentials
and you could capture that so a lot of
major websites have disabled the use of
iframes so you cannot pose as their
website one website that i checked that
does work is bing
so let's switch our url to that save and
reload
yeah see we have embedded the home page
of bing but let's change the width and
height attributes because this is fairly
small let's say the width is
750 pixels and for the height let's say
maybe 250.
so save and reload
cool yeah we have embedded bing within
our webpage and you can use this
normally
bro
code
now let's embed another document so
let's create a new file
let's pretend that this is an
advertisement we would like to display
within our webpage i'll name this
add.html so if you're using vs code to
generate an html document a plain one
type exclamation point then hit tab
so let's say something
i'll use an h1 header tag
this is an advertisement
and then close it uh let's change the
background color too using the style
attribute
and i will pick the background color
property and set this to maybe i don't
know that color uh then let's change the
width and height for the height maybe
then make sure to change your source as
well so we need to list the relative
file path since these files are right
next to each other i only have to list
the file name
add.html save reload
cool and there is my fake advertisement
embedded pages do have a border this is
how to remove that set the style
attribute
equal to the border css property and set
this to zero so i'm going to save reload
and this no longer has that border so
yeah everybody those are iframes they're
used to embed content from another
source into an html document they're
useful for advertisements and they're
easily abused with a lot of hacking
techniques so yeah those are iframes if
you learn something new be sure to smash
that like button drop a random comment
down below and subscribe if you'd like
to become a fellow bro
what's going on everybody it's you bro
hope you're doing well and in this video
i'm going to show you how you can create
a button using html so sit back relax
and enjoy the show
hey in this video i'm going to show you
how we can create buttons using html
we'll need a pair of button tags there's
an opening button tag and a closing
button tag here's our button to add some
text between the button tags we can add
whatever text we want to the button like
click me
you can set this up as a hyperlink when
you click on the button to do so just
surround your button element with a pair
of a tags
there's an opening a tag and a closing a
tag
and i will set the href attribute of the
opening button tag to a url or relative
file path of my choosing to make this
simple let's set the url to google.com
and then when i click on this button it
takes me to google you can disable a
button by adding a disabled boolean
attribute to the opening button tag and
we can no longer click on this button
if you know a little bit of css you can
add some css properties directly to a
button by setting the style attribute
equal to and list some css properties of
your choosing let's change the
background color
you can pick a color name
you can use rgb values
or you can use hexadecimal values
i think i'll set this to a dark gray
color so maybe
6 3s
for rgb values and hexadecimal values
you can always use a color picker online
so if you would like to add multiple css
properties separate each css property
with a semicolon and next i will change
the color that's the font color and
maybe i'll pick green one color i like
is zero zero ff zero zero that's just a
bright green color you can also round
these borders too by using the border
radius property so again separate each
css property with a semicolon
and i will set the border radius
property to 5 pixels just around the
corners
okay cool
that's a pretty fancy looking button if
i do say so myself and yep it still
takes us to google just by us using html
this adds structure to a webpage but it
doesn't necessarily add functionality
that's where a language like javascript
comes in when we click on a button we
can have this button execute some
function from a javascript file i'll
show you how we can create a very simple
javascript program but of course we'll
cover this more in the javascript series
so let's get rid of this hyperlink
and have our button do something else
there is an on
click attribute that we can set to a
javascript function
so we just place the name of the
function between a set of double quotes
we haven't created a javascript function
yet but let's say that we'll have a
javascript function named do something
and then follow that name with a set of
parentheses and let's create a paragraph
element
and we will say hello and then close it
with this paragraph element i'm going to
set the id attribute equal to let's say
test here's how we can code a very
simple javascript program you're going
to create a pair of script tags there's
an opening script tag and a closing
script tag
and within the script i will say
function
do something
parentheses curly braces
so this function will perform some
subsection of code so when we click on
our button what do we want this program
to do we will take document dot
get
element
by id
parentheses
list the id of our paragraph element
test
dot
inner
html
and i will set the sequel to
goodbye
then add a semicolon at the end okay so
when we click on this button it's going
to execute this function do something
and then perform whatever code is
between this set of curly braces
so you may need to save
refresh your web page and if done
correctly when you click on this button
it will change this text
from hello
to goodbye
so that is a very small javascript
program so there is an on click
attribute that you can set equal to a
javascript function but of course we'll
cover more about javascript well in the
javascript playlist but that's one way
in which you can add functionality to a
button in this video we were more
focused on actually creating the button
itself so yeah if this video helped you
out you can help me out by smashing that
like button leave a random comment down
below and subscribe if you'd like to
become a fellow bro
hey everyone i'm going to try and
explain everything i can about forms in
about eight minutes to create a form
element we'll need a pair of form tags
there's an opening form tag and a
closing form tag and depending on the
user input that you need there is an
input element and you can set the type
attribute to whatever you need let's say
we need some text from a user like a
first name within our form there is a
text box where we can enter in some user
information so we should probably let
the user know what we want them to type
in i will precede this input element
with a label
let's say first name and a user can type
in their first name now it is considered
good practice to fill out a for
attribute within the label and set this
to whatever you want let's say fname and
within the associated input elements i
will set the id also equal to fname
whatever's within the four attribute
this does a couple things one if i was
to click on this label this will select
my input box it's also helpful for
people that are using screen readers so
that they can easily navigate your form
there is also a name attribute when we
submit this data what sort of name do we
want to give that data think of it like
a variable i will also name this fname
as well within the input element there
is a placeholder to display some default
text to a user by setting the
placeholder attribute equal to some text
like spongebob so if i was to click
within this input field and type
something that will get rid of my
placeholder let's create an input field
for a last name and really we can just
copy this and make a few changes to it
so copy both the label and the input
element uh let's change this from first
name to last name
change four as well to lname
id will be lname and let's make name l
name as well
and the placeholder how about square
pants
these labels and input elements will
appear on the same line to separate them
and treat them as block level elements i
will add each of these pairs to their
own div element
perhaps i'll add a line break as well
okay now with forms there are built-in
buttons too
we will set the input type equal to
reset so if i were to type in some text
and click reset that will reset
whatever's within my form and there is a
submit button as well
i will set the type equal to submit so
currently our data doesn't have any
place to go to so if i were to click the
submit button this data is not going to
go anywhere so if i need to send this
data to a page i will list that page
within the action attribute of my
opening form element
so we'll need the help of a dynamic
programming language php for example
we're not going to focus on
functionality in this video but rather
the structure of a form so if i need to
send this to
a php page i will list that php page
within the action attribute there is
also an associated method attribute two
common values are get and post
get is considered insecure it's going to
append your data to the url of your web
page so for example if i set the method
to get and type in some information
and click submit it's going to append my
data to the end of my url so it's going
to add a question mark then all of my
data if you need to submit some secure
information like a password do not use
get i would say that this is useful for
things like search boxes if a user needs
to navigate your web page for maybe some
sort of keyword so it's better to use
post to submit some secure information
but this isn't going to do anything
obviously because we do not have a
server set up now there is a required
boolean attribute you can add if
somebody needs to submit some
information they are required to fill
out any input elements that have this
boolean attribute of required so if i
just attempt to submit this without
typing in anything there is a small
pop-up box that says please fill out
this field all right i'm going to go
kind of quick through these next input
elements just because i think we have
the hang of the general context of input
elements so next we have password fields
you set the type equal to password so if
somebody types in characters they will
be hidden if you need to set a max size
of your password there is a max length
attribute let's set this to maybe 12 so
we can type in no more than 12
characters for a password and you can
also add that required boolean attribute
too
for an email element set the type equal
to email
in order to submit an email we need an
at character within our email otherwise
we cannot submit this information and
perhaps i'll add a placeholder as well
placeholder equals s
pants
at gmail.com
so there is our placeholder for a
telephone number you're going to set the
type equal to tell
and i do have a placeholder as well if
you need the user to type in a date like
a birth date there is a type date which
includes an interactive calendar to
select a date
a user can type in a number if you set
the type equal to number let's say that
the user is buying something from a
store there are some arrows where they
can increase or decrease the quantity
but we should probably place some limits
they can type in basically whatever
number they want they want negative one
billion items
so we can set the min and the max i'll
set the min equal to 0 and of the max
equal to what about 99
and you can also set a default value too
i'll set the default value equal to 1.
next we have radio buttons with radio
buttons we can only select one radio
button from any one group perhaps we'll
have the user select a title are they a
mr a miss or a doctor
so i'm going to create a pair of labels
and input for each option that we have
so we will have a mr option
miss
and
phd okay i will set the input type equal
to radio and then do that with each of
these pairs
so we can select more than one because
these are all not within the same group
to set them all within the same group we
will all have them have the same
matching name
let's say that the name will be title
so therefore we can only select one now
since they're all within the same group
and that's kind of the idea behind radio
buttons you can only select one and we
will set an associated value of let's
say mister for the first value
misses for the second
and doctor for the last one
then i'm just going to precede all of
these with a separate label
uh let's say title
and i will set the four attribute equal
to title and within each of these radio
button labels when i click on one of
these labels i also want to be able to
select one of these radio buttons so i
will set the for attribute equal to a
unique id so let's say mister
the id will be mister
and repeat the same steps
okay so when we click on these labels we
should be able to select our radio
buttons
nice with drop down menus instead of a
type we are going to use a pair of
select tags so there's an opening select
tag and a closing select tag and we list
individual options within the select
element
we'll give our user three options from
this drop down menu they can pay with a
visa a mastercard or a gift card
and i will give each of these a value
okay we now have a payment field and the
user can select an option from this drop
down menu
and the last input type i will explain
in this video is the checkbox type so
let's say we have a subscribe button and
you can go ahead and smash that
subscribe button so just set the type
equal to checkbox for well a checkbox
well yeah everybody that's how to create
an html form there's still some more
advanced input types we did not cover
but these are the very basics i would
say if you found this video helpful
please remember to smash that like
button leave a random comment down below
and subscribe if you'd like to become a
fellow bro
you